COTTON CANDY
（棉花糖）
Mom.
妈妈
MAY 1975
（1975年5月）
TODAY IS CHILDREN'S DAY
（今天是儿童节）
Over here!
看这里
CHILDREN ARE OUR COUNTRY'S TREASURE
（儿童是我们国家的珍宝）
ROMANCE
（浪漫号）
ROMANCE 11
（浪漫11号）
Look over there.
看那边
Come closer.
近点
Should we pedal all the way there?
我们要不要蹬到那边去？
Sure. Let's go.
好 出发
Pedal.
快蹬呀
-Faster. -Darn it.
-快点 -糟糕
Hey.
喂
-Hey, look out! -What? Over there!
-喂 小心 -什么？那边
Oh, no. My balloon!
不要 我的气球
Ha-young!
霞永
Please help!
请帮帮我
Please help! I need help over here!
请帮帮我 我需要帮助
-Come on. -The students were messing around.
-快点 -学生们闹着玩的时候
And that kid fell into the water.
那个孩子掉水里了
-My goodness. -That's how they found her.
-天啊 -所以他们才发现了她
Ma'am.
女士
Excuse me. Ha-young.
稍等 霞永
Ha-young.
霞永
You really scared me today.
你今天真是吓死我了
MARCH 1998
（1998年3月）
Hey, did you get anything?
喂 你发现什么了？
Brief me.
跟我报告一下
I haven't seen even a single ant over here.
这里连一只蚂蚁都看不到
Closing news.
最后一条新闻
There have been many cases of break-ins
1997年开始 多户居民家
at multiplex houses since 1997.
遭遇非法闯入
Women were sexually assaulted and robbed.
多名女性遭遇性侵和抢劫
-This is the Red Cap Incident. -None.
-这就是红帽子事件 -什么都没有
It continues to take place.
案件仍层出不穷
-The police haven't made progress. -How much longer?
-警方却并无进展 -还要多久？
So the public is worried for their safety.
民众对自身安全感到担忧
The police announced that they will reinforce the patrol
警方宣布将在小巷和居民区
in alleys and residential areas,
加强巡逻
and they would do their best to arrest the culprit.
同时将尽全力逮捕凶手
Gosh. This is killing me.
天啊 要冻死了
It's March. How come it's still freezing?
都3月了 怎么还这么冷？
It's always cold when we're on a stakeout.
每次潜伏的时候都特别冷
Hey.
喂
This is the basics of a stakeout.
这可是潜伏的基本素养
DONGBU POLICE STATION VIOLENT CRIMES ASSISTANT INSPECTOR SONG HA-YOUNG
（东部警察局重案组 宋霞永警查）
I can't believe we can't even go home
真是不敢相信现在还不能回家
because we have to catch a sex offender.
就为了抓一个强奸犯
What is this?
这算什么事啊？
This has been going on for ten months.
这事已经闹了十个月
And there have been 12 victims.
出现了12个受害者
Besides, this is our job.
再说这是我们的职责
Think about the victims.
想想受害者
Stakeouts are nothing.
我们这点算不上什么劳累
Sure. That's why we must catch him.
对 所以一定要抓住他啊
What if he doesn't show up now that we're waiting for him here?
可是我们在这等着 万一他根本不露面怎么办？
This kind of sting operation has no foundation.
这种诱捕行动准备一点都不充分
We'll put this one-dimensional approach behind
到21世纪我们就能抛弃这种原始手段
in the 21st century and move forward with more futuristic methods, right?
用更先进的未来方法了 对吧？
-What do you mean by futuristic? -I don't know.
-什么是未来方法？ -我也不知道
I'm just frustrated. So I'm spitting out ideas.
我只是心里不痛快 随口说说
I'm frustrated too.
我也不痛快
Gosh. You have to speak up now.
天啊 你一定要现在说
I come here every day, and I only saw one cat.
我天天来这儿 就见过一只猫
Right.
对啊
We'll be back tomorrow anyway.
反正我们明天还会来的
-Take out the walkie-talkie. -Okay.
-把对讲机掏出来 -好
Let's see.
看看
Captain, we'll wrap up for the night.
班长 我们今天就先收工了
Captain, it's snowing. Let's call it a night.
班长 下雪了 今天晚上先这样吧
Okay. Let's wrap it up.
好 收工吧
Come back here tomorrow at 10:00 p.m.
明天晚上10点还来这里
-See you later. -Bye.
-再见
Gosh. It's freezing out here. Let's try again tomorrow.
天啊 外边冻死人了 明天再说吧
-We're wrapping up. Go home. -What?
-我们收工了 回家 -什么？
We can go home?
我们能回家了？
It's so cold.
太冷了
Why is it snowing in March?
3月下什么雪啊？
-Let's go. -It's too early.
-我们也走吧 -太早了
It's 3 a.m. already.
已经凌晨3点了
Here's what I think.
要我说
That punk must know that we're here.
那个混蛋肯定知道我们在这儿
So we should rest up too.
所以我们也应该休息一阵儿
Let's come back when he least expects it.
然后趁他不备再突然袭击
Crime also happens when one least expects it.
罪行也是在不备时发生的
Gosh. I know that.
天啊 我知道了
Who's going to know all the work we do here?
我们这么累又有谁知道呢？
We're not making any progress with our investigation.
我们的调查一直没进展
Darn it.
可恶
People just call the cops incompetent.
人们只会骂警察无能
You go home then. I'll stay a bit longer.
那你回去吧 我再待一会儿
If you do things on your own,
让你一个人留在这儿
Captain Park is going to give me an earful.
朴班长知道了肯定要说我
Will you stay then?
那你想留下吗？
See you later.
再见了
Right.
对了
Don't tell Captain Park about this.
别跟朴班长说这件事
Sure. Go home.
知道了 回去吧
-Bye. -Okay. See you later.
-再见 -好 再见
What do you want to eat?
你想吃什么？
I'm not going to eat.
吃什么吃
Come on. Just show up already.
快点 赶紧现身吧
Red Cap.
红帽子
That's not your house.
那不是你家吧？
Come here.
过来
It won't take long.
用不了多久的
Darn it.
该死
Hey!
喂
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Come here.
别动
Gosh, the weather's so inconsistent.
天啊 这天气变得真快
Why is it raining?
怎么又下雨了？
-Let's go. -Darn it.
-走吧 -该死
He was just pretending to be Red Cap?
他只是假装自己是红帽子？
He has five priors for rape and assault,
他有五项强奸猥亵的前科
but he has an alibi for every Red Cap Incident.
但每次红帽子事件 他都有不在场证据
He did it because the red cap
他这么做是因为只要戴着红色的帽子
makes victims unable to resist due to fear.
就会让受害者因为害怕而无法反抗
DONGBU POLICE STATION
（扣押人员现况）
Take good care of him.
请照顾好他
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATIONS
（刑事股）
What is it?
怎么了？
-Why do you think he did it? -What do you mean?
-你觉得他为什么杀人？ -什么意思？
Hey.
喂
I don't even want to know what scumbags like him are thinking.
我根本不想知道他这种人渣怎么想的
Why?
为什么呢？
That's just how they were born.
他们生来就是人渣
He's not thinking.
能怎么想？
Exactly. We caught him, so why let him mess with you?
对 我们都抓到他了 为什么还要让他干扰你们呢？
Mess with us?
干扰我们？
With our minds.
干扰我们的思想
We already have enough to worry about.
我们要操心的事情够多了
Once the case is closed, it's wise to not think about it again.
案子一结束 就别再想那么多了
Do you ever use your brain to think?
你用脑子想过事情吗？
Let's go eat something.
去吃点东西吧
What do you want?
你想吃什么？
-Not coming, right? -No, go ahead.
-你不来吗？ -不了 你们去吧
Copycat crimes imitating Red Cap are running rampant,
模仿红帽子的犯罪事件日益猖獗
adding further complications to the investigation.
让调查活动变得更加复杂
A special promotion offer is on the table for the officer
抓住凶手的警官将得到特殊晋升
who catches the culprit, but there aren't enough leads on him.
可有关凶手的线索依然少之又少
The first Red Cap Incident took place on May 11, 1997.
第一起红帽子事件发生在 1997年5月11月
He broke into a woman's home in Dongdaemun-gu, Seoul,
他闯入首尔东大门区一位女性家中
raped her, and fled the scene.
实施强奸 随后逃离现场
To date, 12 sexual assault victims have been reported.
时至今日 已报道12位受害者遭到强奸
The culprit is known as "Red Cap"…
凶手被称为红帽子…
-Ms. Choi Hwa-yeon. -Yes.
-崔花妍女士 -是
I booked your next appointment
我把你的下次检查
for the date the doctor suggested.
按医生建议的日期预约好了
Next time, make sure you come with the father.
下次一定要和孩子父亲一起来
Okay, I will.
好 我会的
-Thank you. -Get home safely.
-谢谢你 -回去路上注意安全
Regarding the Red Cap Incident, the police…
针对红帽子事件 警方…
They still haven't caught him?
还没抓到吗？
When will he be caught?
什么时候能抓到啊？
Right? It's so scary.
是吧？太吓人了
SERIAL RAPIST RED CAP'S WHEREABOUTS STILL REMAIN UNKNOWN
（连环强奸犯红帽子仍下落不明）
TURTLE SUPERMARKET
（乌龟超市）
Mom!
妈妈
My gosh.
真是的
You should've just bought an umbrella.
你应该直接买把伞的
You're soaked.
怎么淋着雨过来
-When did you get here? -Goodness.
-你什么时候来的？ -真是的
I brought you winter cabbage and green onion kimchi.
我给你带了冬白菜还有葱泡菜
My gosh, your fridge was a mess.
真是的 你的冰箱乱成什么样了
I threw out the spoiled food and cleaned everything.
我把变质东西扔了 全都清理了一遍
I made barley tea too.
还煮了大麦茶
I can do it too. You always do everything and nag me.
我也能做的 你老是大包大揽还唠叨我
Go inside.
赶紧进去吧
It's raining. You should just sleep here.
还在下雨呢 你在这儿睡吧
Don't stay out too late. My goodness.
太晚就别在外边了 真是的
You're old enough to know that it's a scary world.
都这么大了该知道社会多危险了
Just sleep here tonight.
今晚在这里睡吧
I have to go to work tomorrow.
我明天还要上班呢
Take a taxi. I'll give you the money.
叫出租车吧 我给你钱
Why waste money when I can take the bus?
我坐公交车就行 浪费钱干吗？
-Forget it. -Wait!
-没事的 -等等
All right.
好了
Leave the kimchi out for two days.
泡菜在外边放两天
-That way, it'll age well. -Okay.
-这样才能腌入味 -好
Bye.
再见
You're making me uncomfortable. Just go inside.
别让我难受了 快进去
Get going.
你先走
I'm not a kid.
我又不是小孩子了
Bye.
再见
-Make sure you take a taxi! -Okay.
-一定要叫出租车 -知道了
-Mom! -Yes?
-妈妈 -怎么了？
Bye.
再见
Bye. Don't forget to lock the door.
再见 别忘了锁门
Okay.
好
It's good.
真好吃
You scared me.
你吓死我了
You didn't lock the door.
你没锁门
The landlord had a break-in.
房东都遇到过入室盗窃
Make sure you lock the door.
一定要锁门啊
When did you get here?
你什么时候来的？
-You forgot to take an umbrella, right? -How did you know?
-你忘记带伞了吧？ -你怎么知道？
The floor was wet, so I wiped it.
地板都湿了 我刚擦过了
-Right. -I should've picked you up.
-对 -我应该去接你的
Are you having ramyeon?
你准备吃泡面吗？
You want some too?
你也想吃吗？
I should head back out.
我该回去了
I stopped by to see you before work.
我出摊前过来看看你
Can't you just skip work and stay with me tonight?
你今天就不能休息一天陪陪我吗？
I should work hard to earn more money
我得努力工作挣更多钱
so that you can live comfortably.
才能让你过得更舒服
I don't want to be alone.
我不想一个人
Everyone's rejecting me today.
今天都在拒绝我
-What? -My mom was here.
-什么？ -我妈妈来过
It's just a food stall. Can't you just hang out with me today?
区区一个小吃摊而已 你今天陪陪我不行吗？
"Just a food stall"?
“区区一个小吃摊”？
Sorry. Don't get me wrong.
对不起 我没别的意思
Did you say "just a food stall"?
你刚说“区区一个小吃摊”？
Look at you belittling me again.
你又在小看我
What do you mean again?
什么叫又？
You get all sensitive whenever I talk about the food stall.
每次我提到小吃摊 你都那么敏感
Honestly, it makes you look so insecure!
说真的 你表现得很自卑
You little…
该死
I'm sorry.
对不起
Darn it. What a way to ruin my night.
该死 真扫兴
Breaking news from SBC News.
《SBC新闻》最新消息
We've had a few rainy days in a row.
最近阴雨天气不断
At a house in Daebong-dong, Gwangjin-gu, a woman in her twenties was found dead
在首尔广津区大风洞一处房屋 发现一名20多岁的女性尸体
with all of her clothes undressed.
该名女性全身一丝不挂
Police regarded this
警方将这起案件
as a rape and murder case and launched an investigation.
认定为强奸谋杀案 并展开调查
The police decided to investigate whether this incident
警方决定调查这起案件
was related to the so-called Red Cap Incident,
是否与所谓的红帽子事件有关联
the sexual assault cases that broke out one after another in Seoul.
红帽子事件指的是 在首尔接二连三发生的强奸案
On April 10, a report was made by a woman in her thirties,
4月10日 一名30多岁的女性曾报案称
a victim of sexual assault from Hwayang-dong, Gwangjin-gu.
她是广津区华阳洞的强奸案受害者
May I help you?
你想买什么？
Do you have Little Finger?
你卖那种小手指吗？
I'm craving it.
我想吃那个
The case was transferred to the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
该案已转交首尔地方警察厅
Also, the police are…
同时警方…
TURTLE SUPERMARKET
（乌龟超市）
It's a snack that looks like a pinky, covered in chocolate.
是一种零食 看起来像小手指上蘸满巧克力
You scared me!
你吓死我了
-Look at that. -On the 15th,
-看那个 -15日
-Sorry. -a woman in her twenties
-对不起 -一名20多岁的女性
-You nearly gave me a heart attack. -was found dead in her house.
-差点被你吓出心脏病 -在自己家中被发现死亡
I'm a detective.
我是刑警
-You can relax. -The victim's mother
-你可以放松点 -受害者母亲
couldn't reach her daughter, so she visited her house
打不通女儿电话 才去了她家
-Are you out? I wanted some. -and was the first to see the crime scene.
-没货了吗？我想吃点 -是第一位发现案发现场的人
You said you're a detective!
你不是说自己是刑警嘛
Why do you want a chocolate snack like a kid this late at night?
怎么像孩子一样 这么晚了吃巧克力零食？
-One second. -The investigation began,
-等等 -调查已经展开
but no witness was found.
但是目前没有目击者
These?
这种吗？
Yes.
对
May I have one more?
我可以再要一个吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你
CHOI HWA-YEON'S HOME
（崔花妍家）
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
（正在调查 禁止进入）
Hey, where have you been?
喂 你去哪儿了？
Goodness.
真是的
The victim's mother said her daughter came home around 10 p.m. two days ago.
受害者母亲说 她女儿在两天前晚上10点左右回家
She couldn't reach her so she came here and made a report.
她打不通女儿电话 就来了这里 然后报的案
What about her family?
她的家庭情况呢？
She has a mother,
她有一个母亲
but she was in bad condition and was taken to the hospital an hour ago.
不过母亲身体不好 一个小时前被送到医院了
She was in awful condition,
她情况很差
so I just injected her with a sedative and sleeping agent.
所以我给她 注射了一针镇静剂加安眠药
Whenever he's at the crime scene,
不管他什么时候到犯罪现场
the first thing he does is look for the bereaved family.
第一件事总是先找死者家属
If he was staging this, he couldn't do it for so long.
就算他是装的 也不会装这么久吧
He's an outcast, but he has no idea.
他被孤立了 还毫不知情
That's odd too, isn't it?
太奇怪了 对吧？
Do you think he doesn't know?
你以为他不知道吗？
So he does?
他知道？
Then how can he be so cool about it?
那他还能这么淡定？
Don't you think he's the one casting us out?
你不觉得是他在孤立我们吗？
What?
什么？
I heard he got transferred here because he has always been like this.
我听说就是因为他以前老这副德行 才被调到这里的
Some say he's the nephew of the commissioner.
有人说是因为厅长侄子
The son-in-law of the brother of the third cousin of his in-law.
是亲家的第三个堂弟的兄弟的女婿
Goodness, word gets around weirdly in this industry.
天啊 咱们这行的传言真是奇怪
Captain.
班长
Going back on a case that his direct superior closed.
把上司结过的案子重新拿出来
It's not easy to do that.
一般人可做不出这种事
Just do your job.
做好你的事就行了
Stop minding something unnecessary.
别想些有的没的
And stop talking to me when I eat.
还有我吃饭的时候别跟我说话
Okay.
好
-You're home. -Yes.
-你回来啦？ -对
You look tired. You should go to sleep.
你看着很累 早点休息
I will. Goodnight.
知道了 晚安
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Gil-pyo.
哥
-Come on, Gil-pyo. -Stop following me.
-拜托了 哥 -别跟着我
-Hey, Gil-pyo. -Found it.
-喂 吉票 -找到了
This is really important.
这件事真的很重要
Hey, Red Cap is turning the world upside down.
喂 红帽子把社会搞得乌烟瘴气
Why are you here?
你来这里干什么？
There will come a day when you'll say I was right.
总有一天你会承认我是对的
Hey! I'm about to lose my joints running after this case.
喂 我为这个案子跑得膝盖都脱臼了
-That's because of your age. -Darn you. You won't be young forever.
-那是因为你年纪大了 -该死 你能年轻一辈子嘛
CHIEF OF SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD, HEO GIL-PYO
（机动搜查队队长 许吉票）
We already have Forensics.
我们已经有鉴定组了
We don't have grounds to establish a Scientific Investigations Team.
没理由再建一个科学调查小组
Even an open-hearted guy like me doesn't understand why we need that.
连我这么开明的人都不明白 为什么要建这个小组
But the higher-ups? They won't understand.
高层呢？他们更不明白了
I explained it to you so many times.
我跟你解释那么多次了
You still don't get it?
你怎么还不明白？
We're already short on staff.
我们已经在精简人员了
Would you spend money to make this team?
你愿意花钱建这个小组吗？
-Think about it. -Come on.
-好好想想 -真是
"Hey, you rascal!
“喂 臭小子
"Go catch another criminal if you have time, you foolish kid."
闲得没事赶紧去抓罪犯吧 臭小子”
Wouldn't they say that?
他们不会说这种话吗？
Exactly.
没错
We need that team in order to catch one more criminal.
我们建了这个小组就能多抓一个罪犯
Those who have been here for too long don't speak my language.
前辈们跟我立场不同
Goodness, you didn't know?
真是的 你才发现吗？
The men who have a say in this, those who have been here for too long,
有决定权的人 那些老前辈
hate unfamiliar methods more than bad methods.
讨厌坏主意 更讨厌新思想
So you should give up on your dream.
所以你还是早点放弃梦想吧
A dream is meant to be had.
梦想还是要有的
-Hey, Superintendent Baek. -Hey.
-你好 白科长 -你好
Goodness, what's going on?
天啊 这是怎么了？
Is he still at it about the scientific investigation?
他还念叨着科学调查小组呢？
Tell me about it. We're all busy, but he must be free.
别提了 我们都忙死了 就他闲的
Gil-pyo, do you have to be like this?
吉票 你一定要这样吗？
My dear Chief Kook Young-soo of Forensics,
尊敬的鉴定股长国荣秀
stop talking to me.
请不要再跟我讲话了
You can talk directly to Superintendent Baek Jun-sik.
你可以直接去找白俊植科长
Talk to me about what?
跟我讲什么啊？
-My goodness. -Good grief.
-真是的 -天啊
Do you know how important profilers are?
你们知不知道犯罪侧写师有多重要？
Yes, I do. Pro fliers, like pilots?
我知道 侧写师嘛 跟飞行师一样吧？
If we want to conduct scientific investigations,
我们要成立科学调查小组
do we have to get on a plane too?
是不是也要开飞机？
The higher the building goes, the longer its shadow will be.
楼越高 影子越长
Goodness, that's a famous quote from that ancient show, Chief Inspector.
天啊 是老片《搜查班长》里的 著名台词
I guess Young-soo isn't that young after all.
看来荣秀也不年轻了
With the IMF, the buildings have crashed down.
那些大楼是因为 国际货币基金组织才倒的
What shadow? You must have a lot of time on your hands.
什么影子？你真是闲的没事找事
Listen up.
大家听着
Very soon,
要不了多久
we will see brutal and heinous criminals like the ones in the US.
我们国家也会出现 美国那种残忍恶毒的罪犯
These criminals have no motives.
他们没有动机
Then what do we do?
到时候我们该怎么办？
We have to be prepared to deal with criminals like them!
我们得做好准备应对这种罪犯
Hey!
喂
I can't take this anymore.
我真是受够了
Are you praying for something big to break out?
你是盼着我们这里发生大案吗？
Why don't you go and pray that a huge case will break out,
你怎么不去祈祷发生一个大案
into a bigger one, and into an even bigger one?
然后一个接一个 一个比一个大？
That's not what I meant.
我不是那意思
You know what I mean.
你知道我什么意思
When's Park Chan-ho game?
朴赞浩什么时候比赛？
Young-soo.
荣秀
Let's grab one later.
等会儿我们喝一杯吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
She was pregnant.
她怀孕了？
-Pregnant? -Yes, about 14 weeks.
-怀孕吗？ -是的 大约14周
Man, that son of a bitch.
该死 那个混蛋
She died from asphyxiation due to cervical compression
她死于因颈部压迫和
and mechanical airway obstruction of the nose and mouth.
口鼻机械性气道阻塞导致的窒息
The estimated time of death
推算死亡时间为
is between 10 p.m. to midnight on the 15th.
15日晚10点至12点之间
The temperature of her rectum shows that it was around 10:30 p.m.
直肠温度显示死亡时间是 晚上10点30分左右
The contents of her stomach show
胃内容物显示
she ate something within an hour before her death,
她在死亡前一小时吃了点东西
so around 11 p.m.
所以是11点左右
Other than the victim's mother,
除了受害者母亲
the time of her death coincides with the time of Bang Ki-hoon's visit.
她的死亡时间 和邦期勋来访时间也吻合
But there's no sign of rape.
可是并没有强奸痕迹
Wait. What about her clothes?
等等 她的衣服呢？
There's no sign of rape, but he undressed her?
他把她衣服脱了 却没有强奸痕迹？
It's Bang Ki-hoon for sure.
一定是邦期勋
So Bang Ki-hoon is your friend?
邦期勋是你朋友？
We only went to the same high school.
我们只是高中同学
TEMPORARILY CLOSED DUE TO PERSONAL MATTERS
（因个人原因暂停营业）
Mr. Bang Ki-hoon?
邦期勋先生？
We're from Dongbu Police Station. Come with us.
东部警察局 跟我们走一趟吧
Why should I?
我为什么要去？
Do you know Choi Hwa-yeon?
你认识崔花妍吗？
-She's my girlfriend. -Exactly.
-她是我女朋友 -对
You're arrested for the suspicion of Choi Hwa-yeon's murder.
你因涉嫌谋杀崔花妍被捕了
Murder?
谋杀？
Murder? What do you mean?
谋杀？你什么意思？
Is Hwa-yeon dead?
花妍死了吗？
We can talk about the details at the station.
详细情况我们到局里再谈
You were going to run away?
你还想逃跑？
Too bad.
真不幸
You missed your window by a close call.
就差一点 你错过了
I'm not running away.
我不是准备逃跑的
Do you have an arrest warrant?
你们有逮捕令吗？
Bang Ki-hoon. You have the right to remain silent.
邦期勋 你有权保持沉默
Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
你说的每一句话都将成为呈堂证供
You have the right to an attorney.
你有权聘请律师
Hwa-yeon is dead?
花妍死了？
I didn't do it.
我没杀人
Yes. Right on cue.
对 说得对
That's what everyone says.
每个人都会这么说
I really didn't do it. Why would I…
我真的没杀人 我为什么要…
All the circumstantial evidence is pointing to you.
所有间接证据都指向你
You were at her house at the estimated time of death.
推算死亡时间内你正好在她家
And we also found your fingerprints at her house.
我们还在她家发现了你的指纹
Why would I kill my girlfriend?
我为什么要杀我的女友呢？
Exactly.
对
That's what I would like to know too.
我也想知道这个
Why did you kill your girlfriend?
你为什么要杀你的女友呢？
I didn't kill her.
我没有杀她
Then where did you go after leaving her house?
那么你离开她家后去了哪里？
You didn't work that night.
你那晚没有出摊
You don't have anyone to support your alibi, right?
也没有人能证明你不在场 对吗？
I went to the Han River.
我去了汉江
Come on.
拜托
At least make it sound believable.
编谎话也要编得像一点啊
Is that the best you can do?
你就这点本事吗？
I'm telling the truth.
我说的是真的
We fought that night and I wasn't in the mood to work.
那晚我们吵架了 我没心情出摊
That's it.
就是这样
Your motive for killing Choi Hwa-yeon.
这就是你杀害崔花妍的动机
It was…
那只是…
a small argument.
一次小争吵
Do you kill your girlfriend over some argument you have?
你会因为和女友拌几句嘴就杀人吗？
That's the difference between us.
这就是我们的不同之处
You're sitting there and I'm sitting here.
你坐在那边 我坐在这边
We're only one meter apart.
我们只有一米之隔
But there's a huge gap between our humanity.
但是我们的良心隔了十万八千里
Detective.
警官
I really didn't do it.
我真的没杀人
Are you…
你是…
Red Cap?
红帽子吗？
What?
什么？
We got a report that someone saw a man in a red cap around that time.
我们接到报告说 有人在那晚看到一个戴红帽子的男人
TURTLE SUPERMARKET
（乌龟超市）
A man without an umbrella was walking, not running.
一个男人没打伞走在路上 也不跑
I just thought that it was because he was wearing a cap.
我还想可能因为他戴着帽子吧
Was it red?
是红色吗？
I think it was.
我记得是
-A red cap? -Yes.
-红帽子？ -是的
Do you remember anything else about him?
你还记得他的其他特征吗？
As for his height…
他的身高…
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Anyway, he was pretty short like a girl.
反正他跟女孩子一样矮矮的
Detective.
警官
What can I do to make you believe me?
我要怎么做才能让你相信我？
Show me evidence you didn't do it. Then I'll believe you.
给我看你没杀人的证据 我就相信你
We only believe in evidence.
我们只相信证据
But you don't have evidence. Do you?
可是你没有证据 对吧？
The door.
门
The door wasn't locked.
门没锁
Think carefully before you speak.
想清楚了再说
This statement could work against you.
这个供词可能对你不利
I'm not the one.
我不是凶手
You have a record for assault.
你有暴力犯罪前科
And pretending you left the gang with that food stall.
还开了小吃摊假装离开黑社会了
I'm not pretending. I'm done with that life.
不是假装 我已经不过那种生活了
Whatever it is, I don't care.
随便吧 我不关心
But people like you get hot-tempered just like now.
不过你这种人就是会像刚才一样冲动
And when you do,
一旦冲动起来
you unintentionally end up hurting people, right?
就会失手伤害别人 对吧？
Just be honest.
说实话吧
I don't kill people.
我没杀人
Are you a gang member who has a heart?
你是那种有人性的黑社会吗？
Did your dead girlfriend know
你死去的女友知道
that you used to be in a gang?
你以前混黑社会吗？
Then did you know…
那你知道…
that Choi Hwa-yeon was pregnant?
崔花妍已经怀孕了吗？
What do you mean?
那是什么意思？
Given that you were dating,
你们既然是男女朋友
you two kept a lot of secrets from each other.
还相互隐瞒了这么多秘密呢
I'm telling you.
我跟你说吧
You can't just rely on tangible evidence.
你不能只依赖实物证据
Well, without the evidence, we'd be shooting blind.
没有证据 我们就像盲人打枪了
Then what do you suggest?
你有什么建议？
What should we rely on?
我们应该依赖什么？
-How they prepared to commit crimes. -Right.
-犯罪的准备过程 -对
And how and why they committed crimes.
还有犯罪的过程和动机
And how the corpses were handled.
还有尸体的处理方式
We should be studying the entire process.
我们要研究整个过程
-Right. And scientifically too. -Yes.
-对 还要科学地学习 -没错
Science.
得科学啊
Come on. Stop talking about science.
得了吧 别说科学了
Hold on.
等等
Do you have to get the license to be a pilot or whatever that's called?
得拿到驾照才能当飞行师吗 那个到底叫什么？
What? Why are you laughing?
怎么了？你们笑什么？
Are you Choi Bool-am or what? "Pilot"?
你以为自己是崔佛岩吗？还飞行师？
-Gosh. You're so frustrating. -You're frustrating.
-真是的 你真让人发愁 -真让人发愁
It's not a pilot. It's a profiler.
不是飞行师 是侧写师
-Right. A profil… -A profiler.
-对 侧写… -侧写师
A profiler.
侧写师
All right. I'm sorry.
好了 不好意思
By the way, who's going to do that?
对了 找谁来做那个呢？
I know just the guy.
我刚好认识一个人
He's more stubborn than I am.
他比我还难搞
-Gosh. He sounds like trouble. -Goodness.
-真是的 听着就是个刺头 -真是
TEMPORARILY CLOSED DUE TO PERSONAL MATTERS
（因个人原因暂停营业）
Bang Ki-hoon. Did you really do it?
邦期勋 真的是你杀的吗？
Gosh, he's taking a while.
真是的 他去那么久
There were a lot of petty thieves in that neighborhood.
那片居民区有很多小偷
The landlord on the second floor was robbed of their valuables too.
二楼房东家里的贵重物品也被偷过
When?
什么时候？
About a month ago.
一个月前
Their house had a smart door lock.
二楼那家是智能门锁啊
When did you check that?
你什么时候发现的？
Wait. Are you going there?
等等 你要去那里吗？
Gosh. You really shouldn't.
天啊 你最好别去
You killed a person. You bastard.
你杀了人 混蛋
You scum.
人渣
You should feel guilty.
你应该感到内疚
What?
怎么了？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Getting a confession out of him.
让他招供啊
Close the door.
关门
We're not done, you piece of trash.
跟你还没完呢 垃圾
You jerk.
混蛋
What's the problem? What is it?
什么事？怎么了？
Do you think this kind of confession is valid?
你觉得这种供词可靠吗？
Don't act all righteous and lecture me.
别多管闲事来说教我
Get back to work.
回去工作吧
This is my work too.
这也是我的工作
Gosh. Come on.
真是的 该死
Get out.
出去
He can't even give me his alibi right now.
他现在连不在场证明都拿不出来
Why? Because he killed her.
为什么？因为他杀了她
You know he was there at the estimated time of death.
你知道推算死亡时间内他正好在场吧
Your friend from school fought with Choi Hwa-yeon that day.
你的老同学那天和崔花妍吵架了
He didn't call her for a few days, so he had no idea she was dead.
他好几天没给女友打电话 所以根本不知道她死了
-You think that makes any sense? -She was pregnant.
-你觉得这符合常理吗？ -她怀孕了
Bang Ki-hoon might not be the culprit.
邦期勋也许不是凶手
You think murderers have mercy?
你以为杀人犯还会有慈悲之心吗？
They don't.
没有的
But it was too bad for him.
不过也算他倒霉
He didn't even know she was pregnant.
他连女友怀孕都不知道
Hey.
喂
She must have hidden the fact that she was pregnant for a reason.
她隐瞒自己怀孕的事肯定是有原因的
Even if I want to be lenient with him, I can't.
就算我想对他宽宏大量也没办法了
Even his motive is crystal clear.
连杀人动机都那么明确
These gangsters will never learn.
这种混黑社会的都本性难移
They get hot-tempered and cause trouble.
他们就是会冲动行事 制造麻烦
They are dumb to stage a perfect crime,
没那个智商制造完美犯罪
but they don't want to serve time.
还不想坐牢
But you still want to believe that guy?
你怎么现在还想相信那个人？
That's not what I'm saying.
我不是那个意思
I just want to find definitive evidence.
我只是想找到确切证据
You said you weren't friends with him.
你说你不是他朋友
Then listen up.
那就听好了
Those bastards…
那些混蛋…
don't deserve to be called human.
不配做人
And beating those scumbags is the fastest and the easiest way.
制服那种混蛋 最快最简单的办法就是拳头
But this is still wrong.
可这终究是不对的
I know why you got kicked out of Jungbu Police Station,
我知道你为什么会被踢出中部警察局
but don't try to police your supervisors by nitpicking us.
但是你别想找我们的茬 对上司指手画脚
Just get out there and catch criminals.
赶紧出去抓罪犯吧
Just go out there. You have a lot of work to do.
赶紧出去吧 你还有那么多工作呢
Hey.
喂
Investigate him in connection with the Red Cap case.
调查他跟红帽子案有没有关系
Yes, sir.
知道了
But he didn't rape her, and the method is different.
可是他没有强奸受害者 而且犯罪手法也不同
Such perverted acts are no different from rape.
这种变态行为跟强奸没什么区别
Wait, where are you going?
等等 你想去哪儿？
To find evidence.
去找证据
My goodness.
天啊
The first reason why Ki-hoon isn't the killer.
邦期勋不是凶手的第一个理由
There are signs of forced entry.
有撬锁进入的痕迹
The second reason why he isn't the killer.
他不是凶手的第二个理由
Choi Hwa-yeon was pregnant.
崔花妍怀孕了
Then did you know…
那你知不知道…
that Choi Hwa-yeon was pregnant?
崔花妍怀孕了？
But he didn't know, and he denied all charges.
可是他不知道 而且他否认所有指控
The first reason why Ki-hoon is the killer.
邦期勋是凶手的第一个理由
His prints and blood were found at the scene.
犯罪现场有他的指纹和血迹
The second reason why he is the killer.
他是凶手的第二个理由
The estimated time of death also matches.
符合推算死亡时间
That bastard…
那个混蛋…
Your little friend from school
你的老同学
fought with Choi Hwa-yeon that day.
那天和崔花妍吵架了
Clear motive. Reason number three.
动机明确 第三个理由
Show me evidence you didn't do it. Then I'll believe you.
给我看你没杀人的证据 我就相信你
He has no alibi.
他没有不在场证明
Reason number four.
第四个理由
He entered through the door instead of the window.
他通过大门进入而不是窗户
I should really move.
我真该搬家了
Petty thieves are one thing, but someone died.
有小偷是一方面 现在还死了人
I'm so terrified I can't live here anymore.
我快吓死了 在这里住不下去了
Even I'm this scared.
连我都这么害怕
So I'm worried the house won't sell.
所以这房子也不好卖出去了
Who else had break-ins in this area?
这一片还有谁家遭到入室盗窃？
There were three to four other cases, just counting the ones I heard of.
算上我知道的 总共有三四家
That's the problem.
不过啊
The stolen goods aren't that valuable, so the cops don't care.
被偷的东西不贵重 所以警察不上心
It's been so long.
都过去这么久了
If it was a rich family, the thief would be in jail.
换成有钱人家 小偷早被抓进去了
Was there another break-in downstairs before this incident?
谋杀案发生前 楼下有没有发生过入室盗窃？
No, not that I know of.
没有 反正我没听说
Okay, thank you for your cooperation.
好的 谢谢你的配合
Detective.
警官啊
Can you catch the thief who stole my jewelry
调查杀死楼下小姑娘的混蛋时
while tracking down the jerk who killed the lady downstairs?
能不能也抓住偷我珠宝的小偷啊？
Okay. Just a moment, please.
好 稍等一下
Ma'am, these numbers here.
女士 这些数字
Did you write them?
是你写的吗？
What is that?
什么啊？
My goodness.
天啊
Why would I doodle on the wall? I'm not a kid.
我在墙上乱画干吗？又不是小孩子
Maybe my granddaughters wrote them when they came over.
可能是小孙女们过来时乱画的
Anyway, thank you.
算了 谢谢你
Detective, please catch that thief.
警官 一定要抓住小偷啊
THEFT REPORT
（盗窃案报告）
Five cases were reported in total.
总共有五起案子
There was a break-in every two weeks until three months ago.
三个月前每两周就发生一次入室盗窃
The last one was the two-story house at 214 Daebong-dong?
最后一起是在 大风洞214号的两层小楼？
Yes, this jerk is clever.
是的 这个混蛋很精明
He never breaks into houses with men.
他从不闯进有男人的人家
And only steals cheap items.
而且只偷便宜东西
It's so petty that there are no leads on him whatsoever.
真气人啊 没有他的任何线索
So Dongbu Police Station has given up.
所以东部警局就放弃了
We've enhanced patrols in the area.
我们已经加强了当地巡逻的警力
Thankfully, it's been quiet since then.
还好从那时候开始一直风平浪静
Okay, thank you.
好 谢谢你
DAEBONG PRECINCT
（大风洞派出所）
Daebong-dong, 183-10.
大风洞183之10号
The number, 233.
数字233
Hey! Who are you?
喂 你是谁？
-What are you doing? -Hold on!
-你在干什么？ -别打
-Ma'am, hold on! -Why are you lurking around?
-女士 别打了 -你鬼鬼祟祟干吗呢？
-I'm a police officer! -Why? What?
-我是警察 -什么？你说什么？
I'm a police officer.
我是警察
Then why didn't you ring the doorbell?
那你怎么不按门铃啊？
Why did you lurk around my house? It looked so suspicious.
你在我家外边鬼鬼祟祟干吗呢？ 看着怪可疑的
-My gosh. -I'm sorry. It was getting late.
-天啊 -对不起 这么晚打扰你了
What can I do for you?
你有什么事？
I have a few questions.
我想问几个问题
What is it?
什么问题？
Do you happen to know what these numbers are for?
你知道这些数字什么意思吗？
That's not my address.
这不是我家门牌号
What is it?
那是什么？
-Mom. -Yes?
-妈妈 -怎么了？
Why did you come out?
你们出来干什么？
Who's in your family?
你家里都有谁？
Me and my kids. Just the three of us.
我和孩子们 就我们三个
What about your husband?
你丈夫呢？
Why do you ask?
问这个干吗？
I'm investigating the area.
我在调查这一片
We don't live together.
我们不在一起生活
I see. I'm sorry.
知道了 很抱歉
You don't think your kids wrote the numbers, do you?
你觉得不是你家孩子写的 对吗？
They're not tall enough to reach that high.
他们不够高 够不到那个地方
I see.
知道了
Thank you for your cooperation.
谢谢你的配合
Sure. Come on. Let's go back inside.
没事 走吧 我们进去
Bye, Mr. Policeman.
再见 警察叔叔
-Hurry, go inside. -Goodbye.
-快走 进去吧 -再见
-Gosh, this neighborhood. -Sorry.
-这个小区真是的 -抱歉
Daebong-dong, 190-3.
大风洞190-3号
The number, 22.
数字是22
Who do you live with?
你和谁一起住？
Just me and my sibling. Why do you ask?
只有我和兄弟姐妹 问这个干吗？
Your sibling? Sister or brother?
兄弟姐妹？是姐妹还是兄弟？
Sister.
姐妹
Who do you live with?
你和谁一起住？
I live alone.
我自己住
My mom. It's just the two of us.
我妈妈 就我们两个
The number is on every third house.
每三家就有一个数字
Who do you live with?
你和谁一起住？
I live with my wife. What's this about?
我和我老婆 问这个干吗？
-Who is it? -Hello.
-谁呀？ -你好
My wife and I live here with our ten-year-old son.
我老婆和我 还有我们十岁的儿子
Choi Hwa-yeon's landlord's house had 233.
崔花妍的房东家是233
The house with two kids also had 233 written on the wall.
有两个孩子那家墙上写的也是233
These numbers seem random.
这些数字似乎没有规律
What could they mean?
会是什么意思呢？
Gosh, that bastard. He should watch out.
该死 这小子 骑车要小心点啊
Maybe my granddaughters wrote them when they came over.
也许是我孙女们过来时乱画的
Me and my kids. Just the three of us.
我和孩子们 就我们三个
DO YOUR DUTY
（尽职尽责）
The restaurants in this area.
这片区域的餐厅
How many of them offer delivery?
有多少家提供外卖服务？
-Delivery? -See these numbers?
-外卖？ -看到这些数字了吗？
What is this?
这是什么？
It shows who lives in the house.
它代表了屋里住的人员
Two for women. Three for kids. And one…
2是女性 3是孩子 1…
means an adult male.
指的是成年男性
The culprit avoided houses where men live.
凶手会躲过有男性的房子
He only targeted houses with women and kids.
只对屋里有女性和孩子的房子下手
But what does that have to do with delivery?
可是这和外卖有什么关系呢？
It has to be someone with a job…
因为一这是能确定
that can figure out who lives in the house.
屋内居住人员的工作
BREAKING NEWS
（新闻速报）
Breaking news.
插播新闻速报
The serial rapist known as "Red Cap,"
让居住在首尔的女性
who has made women living in Seoul fall in deep terror,
胆战心惊的连环强奸犯红帽子
was arrested last night.
已于昨晚被捕
You're heading out already?
这么早就要出去？
-Yes. -Dongbu Police Station officers
-是 -东部警察局警察
-Gosh, isn't that your district? -went to the scene after a report
-天啊 那不是你们辖区吗？ -接到报案后赶往现场
and arrested the suspect.
逮捕了嫌犯
The suspect was caught red-handed, wearing his red cap.
嫌犯被当场抓获 当时还戴着红帽子
He admitted all charges and confessed he was the culprit
他承认了所有指控 并承认自己就是
of the Red Cap serial murder case.
红帽子连环杀人案的真凶
Do you admit to everything?
你承认一切罪行吗？
-A comment, please. -Anything to say to the victim's family?
-请讲几句吧 -有什么想对受害者家人说的吗？
-A comment! -Move back!
-请讲几句 -回来
-Look here! -Say something!
-看这里 -说几句吧
-Why did you do it? -How do you feel now?
-你为什么那么做？ -你现在什么感觉？
-Just a comment! -Wait!
-讲几句就行 -等等
Do you admit to all charges?
你承认所有指控吗？
-Just a comment!
-讲几句吧
Unlike the previous cases that took place in the victims' homes.
与以往发生在受害者家中案件不同
-This incident took place… -How dare you smirk? Is this funny?
-本次案件发生在… -你还敢笑？很好笑吗？
Request an arrest warrant.
申请一个逮捕令
Yes, sir.
知道了
Detective, it really wasn't me.
警官 真的不是我
Why would I kill Hwa-yeon?
我为什么要杀花妍？
-Sit down. -That scum.
-坐下 -那个人渣
Song Ha-young, right?
你是宋霞永吧？
The culprit picked the lock.
凶手是撬锁进去的
Look, these numbers…
看这些数字…
Your friend already confessed.
你朋友已经招了
Goodness. Should I go to a temple somewhere and pray?
真是的 我是不是应该找个寺庙拜一拜啊？
Talk about bad timing.
时间真是不巧啊
How could he kill his own girlfriend?
他怎么能杀自己女友呢？
It really wasn't me. Please believe me.
真的不是我 请相信我
Hey, I've seen plenty of scumbags
喂 我见过多少人渣
who killed their wives, daughters,
杀妻 杀女
and even their own parents in the spur of the moment.
甚至还有一时冲动杀害父母的
A girlfriend? That's nothing.
杀女友？根本不算什么
Goodness, me and my bad luck.
天啊 我真是背时
I caught a murderer,
明明是我抓了凶手
but that bastard is getting all the spotlight now.
现在风头全让那个混蛋抢走了
They only care because she was pregnant.
他们这么关心 不过是因为她怀孕了
Why did he take her clothes off?
他为什么要把她衣服脱下来？
I guess he's a twisted pervert.
可能就是精神扭曲的变态吧
You expect me to know his sexual preferences too?
你觉得我会知道他的性癖吗？
If you're that curious, just ask his friend over there.
既然你这么好奇 不如问问他朋友
That guy isn't the culprit.
那家伙不是凶手
Get up and follow me.
起来跟我走
Going to the Special Crime Squad?
去机动搜查队吗？
Why would I go there? We're the ones who caught him.
去那里干吗？是我们把他抓住的
All right.
知道了
The lucky ones always fall on a pile of gold.
走运的人总能捡到金子
Hey!
喂
I know you're Red Cap.
我知道你是红帽子
Why?
为什么？
Do you wish I wasn't?
你希望我不是吗？
You're nothing but a little puppy.
你啥也不是 就是个小屁孩
Don't try to act tough.
别装硬汉了
That guy isn't the culprit.
那个人不是凶手
Is Bang Ki-hoon the real culprit?
邦期勋是真凶吗？
His eyes weren't that of a criminal's eyes though.
他的眼神不像杀人犯的眼神
Detective.
警官
Please…
请你…
Do everything you can to catch the guy
一定要抓住那个
who killed my daughter.
杀害我女儿的家伙
Choi Hwa-yeon's boyfriend, Bang Ki-hoon.
崔花妍的男友邦期勋
He's the culprit.
是凶手
Did you say "boyfriend"?
你说男友？
Hwa-yeon had a boyfriend?
花妍有男友？
She hid her pregnancy and even the fact that she had a boyfriend.
她隐瞒了怀孕 甚至隐瞒了有男友的事
Is Bang Ki-hoon the real culprit?
邦期勋真的是凶手吗？
Goodness me.
天啊
Of all the things to take after me, it had to be my bad luck with men.
学我什么不好 偏偏学我遇到坏男人
I'm so sorry, Hwa-yeon.
我对不起你 花妍
I'm sorry, Hwa-yeon.
对不起 花妍
I should have stayed with her that day.
我那天应该陪着她的
She asked me to sleep over.
她让我留下来睡觉
She offered, but I declined.
她让我留下 可我没答应
It's not your fault.
不是你的错
I should have died instead of Hwa-yeon.
我应该替我们花妍死的
My gosh, Hwa-yeon.
天啊 花妍
Goodness.
天啊
SOONAE HOSPITAL EMERGENCY ROOM
（顺爱医院急诊室）
CHIEF OF FORENSICS KOOK YOUNG-SOO
（鉴定股长 国荣秀）
Hello?
喂？
Chief, this is Ha-young.
股长 我是霞永
Yes?
是哦
I have a favor to ask.
我想请你帮个忙
-You're here. -Yes.
-你来了啊？ -对
Here.
给你
Gosh.
唉唷
Where is it?
在哪里？
They may have missed something the first time.
第一次鉴定可能会漏掉什么东西
The prints were only on the cup.
只有杯子上有指纹
If Bang Ki-hoon cleaned it all up, why would he have left just this?
如果邦期勋都清理干净了 为什么偏偏留下这里？
Everything matches.
一切都符合
From his fingerprints, bloodstain, and time of death.
从他的指纹、血迹还有死亡时间
He even confessed.
更何况他都认罪了
That's true, but…
确实 可是…
You just got to Dongbu Station.
你刚调到东部警局没多久
Will you be okay?
这么做没关系吗？
I came because you asked,
我是因为你的请求才来的
but just as a case is important,
不过案子再重要
-relationships are also-- -You're right.
-人际关系也一样… -你说得对
But catching the culprit is the most important.
可抓住凶手才是最重要的
You never give in to anything.
你真是从不妥协
I heard the suspect is your friend.
听说嫌犯是你朋友
Did you do a background check?
你做过背景调查吗？
That's nonsense.
这是什么话
I call it "having interest."
我说这叫“关心”
We're basically strangers.
我们和不认识没什么区别
Being friends doesn't change anything.
就算是朋友也改变不了什么
As I told you earlier…
我刚才说过…
All right, I got it.
好了 我知道了
I'm good with just our relationship.
只有我们的关系就够了
That's why I couldn't refuse. You know that, right?
所以我才不忍拒绝 你知道的吧？
Thank you.
谢谢你
Express it a little for me then.
那就给我表示表示吧
-Here? -No, forget it.
-在这里吗？ -算了吧
The fact the culprit was calm enough to erase his footprints and fingerprints
凶手冷静到会清除脚印和指纹
means that the crime was most likely planned.
说明这起案件很可能是有预谋的
A woman living alone in a one-bedroom…
一个女性独自住在这种一居室…
The killer may have been hiding and waiting.
凶手可能早早藏起来等待时机
Either underneath this bed…
要么是在床下…
or behind here.
要么是在这后边
Hey. Have you gone mad?
喂 你疯了吗？
Damn it.
该死
Why did you ask to run prints on a case that's closed?
你为什么要求 对已经结案的案子进行指纹检测？
Why?
为什么？
You said that Bang Ki-hoon isn't your friend!
你不是说邦期勋不是你朋友吗？
That's not the reason.
不是因为那个
Friend or not. This case is over.
不管是不是朋友 案子都已经结了
Bang Ki-hoon confessed!
邦期勋已经认罪了
That's because you forced a confession--
那是因为你刑讯逼供…
You're a complete lunatic, aren't you?
你真是疯子吧？
Is Bang Ki-hoon stupid?
邦期勋傻吗？
Why would he lie?
他为什么要撒谎？
He did say he didn't kill her.
他说过他没杀人
Damn you, you crazy bastard.
可恶 你这个疯子
Is it your hobby to screw your superiors over?
忤逆上司是你的爱好吗？
What's the problem?
到底怎么回事？
I'm just saying Bang Ki-hoon may not be the culprit.
我只是说邦期勋可能不是凶手
If he's not…
如果他不是…
If Bang Ki-hoon isn't the culprit…
如果邦期勋不是凶手…
What are you going to do about it?
你想怎么办？
If that's the case, we'll have a bigger problem.
如果是这样 我们就会有大麻烦
You know that.
你知道的
-Know what? You bastard! -Captain!
-知道什么？你这个混蛋 -班长
-You know? -Calm down.
-你知道？ -冷静
-You know nothing! -Please!
-你什么都不知道 -消消气
Step outside for a moment, please!
请你先出去一会儿吧
Calm down, Captain.
冷静 班长
Hey!
喂
You'd better fix your attitude if you want to keep this career.
你还想保住工作的话 最好把态度给我改一改
You got it?
听见没有？
DETECTIVE DIVISION
（刑事科）
-Yes? -Inspector Song Ha-young?
-喂？ -宋霞永警察吗？
I'm calling to notify you that the fingerprint results are in.
打电话是通知你指纹检测结果出来了
But we were unable to confirm the identity.
可是我们无法确认身份
I understand the frustration,
我知道你心里不舒服
but you have to accept the outcome.
可是结果就是这样
-You're here. -Yes.
-你来了 -是
My instincts are telling me otherwise.
我的直觉告诉我不是这样
I know we can't take a detective's instincts lightly.
我知道我们不能轻视刑警的直觉
But we have definite evidence and his confession too.
可现在证据确凿 而且他已经认罪了
That's true, but…
没错 可是…
The fact that the victim's wallet disappeared,
受害者的钱包不见了
how she was left undressed,
她一丝不挂
and the trace of breaking in.
还有撬门的痕迹
And the suspicious numbers on the walls.
还有墙上的可疑数字
All those things are bothering me.
我就是忘不了这些事情
If it were a premeditated crime,
如果是有预谋的犯罪
why was she left undressed?
为什么她会一丝不挂？
The killer must've been busy covering up.
凶手一定急着掩盖
Have you heard about profilers?
你听说过侧写师吗？
We call them criminal behavioral analysts.
我们国家起名叫犯罪行为分析师
You have all the qualifications…
你非常符合…
a profiler needs.
侧写师的要求
First, your refusal to give up.
首先你从不妥协
-All detectives-- -You also have an open mind.
-所有刑警都… -你思想开明
Intuition, general knowledge, and the skill to analyze logically.
直觉 常识 还有逻辑分析的能力
And also a detachment of personal feelings.
还有不掺杂个人情感
But more important than all that…
不过最最重要的是…
The thing I find most important is sensitivity.
我发现最重要的是悟性
"Sensitivity"?
悟性？
Would it be easier to understand if I say sensitivity towards others?
如果我说对他人的领悟力 是不是更好理解？
Why would you need that?
你为什么想做这个？
Because it's a job that analyzes people's minds.
因为这是分析人的思想的工作
Goodness. You only say the most confusing things.
天啊 总说些让人听不懂的话
Hey, take this.
给你
Give it a read when you have time.
有空好好看看
And have some of these when you have time.
有空也吃点这个
Thank you. What is this?
谢谢你 这是什么？
I'm making an attempt to form a new team.
我准备组建一个新团队
I think I found the right guy…
我觉得我找到了合适的人选…
as a criminal behavioral analyst.
做犯罪行为分析师的人
It's the perfect job for someone like you.
让你这样的人来做再合适不过了
I'm fine with what I do now.
我挺喜欢现在的工作
Hey, if you turn me down just like that, you'll hurt my feelings.
喂 你这么直接拒绝我 我会伤心的
It's tough to tell…
还有…
what you're thinking.
你难以看透的表情
But that's also a strength for a profiler.
也是做侧写师的优点
Are you teasing me?
你在嘲笑我吗？
No, I'm very serious.
不是 我说真的
You don't have to decide right away.
你不必马上决定
It'll take some time to make the team.
组建团队还要花些时间
But for now, just remember that there is
不过现在 只要记住
something like this.
有这么回事
Where do you think you're going?
你想去哪儿？
You knocked her out. Then what?
你把她打昏了 然后呢？
Yes, you got on top of her.
对 你骑在她身上
And strangled her, right?
把她掐死了 对吧？
How did you do it?
你是怎么做的？
SUSPECT
（嫌犯）
Her neck.
她的脖子
You strangled her, right?
你把她掐死了 对不对？
Man, this guy is driving me insane.
该死 我要被这家伙逼疯了
Hey, your hands weren't like that.
喂 你的手不是那么放的
You pushed your hands up to her chin and strangled her.
你是拿手顶住她的下巴 然后把她掐死的
Start pressing.
开始用力
You did this, so why don't you remember?
你明明做过 怎么会不记得了？
Do it.
快点
We're running out of time. Hurry up.
我们快没时间了 快点
Keep taking the video.
继续拍视频
After you strangled her, what's next?
你把她掐死了 然后呢？
And then what? You unbuttoned her shirt.
然后呢？你把她衣服解开了
Take her clothes off.
快把她衣服脱下来
-Why did you kill your girlfriend? -All right.
-你为什么要杀你女友？ -好了
Tell us the motive of your murder!
跟我们说说你的动机吧
Bring my daughter back!
把我的女儿还给我
The victim lost her irreplaceable and precious life
受害者在花一样的年纪
at such a young age.
失去了无可替代的宝贵生命
It is clear the victim's family will live in pain
很显然受害者的家人也将在痛苦中
for the rest of her life, along with a psychological shock.
忍受着心理创伤度过余生
The crime of taking another person's life
夺走他人生命的罪行
is serious and unacceptable.
是残酷而不可原谅的
And the accused did not reflect on his crime
被告人对罪行没有反省之心
despite his history of assault.
尽管他前科累累
It was concluded that his crime was heinous.
他的罪行可以说令人发指
Hence, the court sentences Bang Ki-hoon, the accused,
因此法院判决被告邦期勋
to 12 years in prison.
有期徒刑12年
INVESTIGATION RECORD CASE CLOSED
（调查记录 已结案）
North Korea test-fired a new ballistic missile today.
今天朝鲜试射了一枚新的弹道导弹
Today at 5:40 p.m., with the sound of a foghorn,
今天下午5点40分 伴随着雾角声
a historic departure was made for Mount Geumgang…
金刚山开启了历史性的分离…
The EU's unified currency, Euro,
欧盟推出统一货币欧元
was launched to unite the 300 million Europeans
以此团结三亿欧洲人
into one economic bloc.
形成一个经济集团
Sin Chang-won was finally caught.
申昌源终于被捕
The escape of the century, starring Sin Chang-won,
多亏一位市民的举报 这场由申昌源
came to an end this afternoon thanks to a civilian's report.
主导的世纪越狱事件于今天下午落幕
Let's hear more about this story
下面请听来自记者崔龙范
from Reporter Choi Yong-beom.
关于此事件的详细报道
Believe in Christ, go to heaven.
信耶稣上天堂
Disbelief will send you to hell.
不信耶稣下地狱
Believe in Christ,
信耶稣
and you shall go to heaven.
上天堂
If you do not, you'll be sent to hell.
不信耶稣下地狱
Believe in Christ…
信耶稣…
The police…
警察…
I'm back.
我回来了
-You brought it back? -Goodness, you didn't have to.
-你还带回来了？ -天啊 不用带的
It didn't take long.
没花多长时间
Good work, Kang-moo. You should go home.
做得好 江武 快回家吧
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你
-Good work today. -Good work.
-今天辛苦了 -辛苦了
Take good care of your grandma.
照顾好你奶奶
-Okay. Goodbye. -Bye.
-好的 再见 -再见
He's very diligent, unlike other kids these days.
他多努力啊 不像现在的孩子
I hope my son can be half the man Kang-moo is.
要是我儿子跟江武有一半像就好了
Teens these days are all like your kid.
现在的年轻人都跟你家孩子一样
He's the odd one out.
他与众不同
Whenever he gets paid,
不管什么时候拿到钱
he takes it to his grandmother.
都会给奶奶
There's no kid like him these days.
现在他这样的孩子根本没有了
Does he think he's my dad or what?
真把自己当我爸爸了吗？
SUNGWON RESTAURANT
（成元餐厅）
STAY TUNED FOR THE EPILOGUE
（稍后播出后记）
Ha-young, what did you do with your friends today?
霞永 你今天和朋友做什么了？
This lady looks sad.
这个姐姐看起来很伤心啊
-Yes. -Why is she sad?
-是的 -她为什么伤心呢？
Do you know how scary it is
你知道
when you're deep underwater?
在深水里有多可怕吗？
YOUNGSHIN SUPERMARKET
（荣信超市）
She must've been scared and sad.
她肯定又害怕又伤心
Her mom isn't there in the water.
水里是没有妈妈的
Ha-young.
霞永
Come here.
过来
It's not that Ha-young isn't sympathetic.
霞永不是没有同情心
He's very sympathetic.
他太有同情心了
I'm not sure if you'll understand.
我不确定你能否理解我的话
But he can look deeply into people's inner sides.
不过他能看透人的内心深处
Their inner sides?
内心深处？
Ha-young. What about your umbrella?
霞永 你的雨伞呢？
I gave you an umbrella this morning.
我今天早上给了你一把雨伞
Where is it?
去哪儿了？
Ha-young is only nine years old.
霞永只有九岁
It's because he's a child.
因为他还是个孩子
He sees a difference between his feelings and other people's reactions.
他明白个人感受 和他人反应之间的区别
He must have realized that he is different from others.
他一定是明白了自己和别人不一样
Seeing the dead body that day…
那天看到那具尸体…
triggered this thought in his head.
激发了他脑子里的这种思想
So he's trying to hide his emotions.
所以他尝试隐藏自己的感受
Don't worry, Ha-young.
别担心 霞永
I will bury it in a nice place.
妈妈会好好安葬它的
Come here.
来抱抱
I want to know why you thought he didn't do it.
我想知道你为什么觉得他不是凶手
If you don't catch him, it'll happen again.
如果你们不抓到他 凶案还会继续发生
Detective Song of Dongbu Police Station went to Yang Yong-chul,
东部警察局的宋刑警探访
an inmate in prison, and received help from him.
关押的梁龙哲 并向他寻求帮助
This news shocked the public.
使民众无比震惊
That a detective keeps visiting him and asking him for advice!
有个刑警一直去找他 询问他的意见
Criminals understand each other better.
罪犯更能理解罪犯的心理
I think we can finally form the Behavioral Analysis Team.
我们终于能组建出行动分析小组了
Others couldn't understand, but you instinctively knew this was necessary.
其他人不理解 可是你本能觉得应该那样做
I'm certain that you're the perfect person for this job.
你就是这个工作的最佳人选